Guide to the Constance Webb Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Constance Webb Papers,
1918-2005
[Bulk Dates: 1939-2002].
Webb, Constance
9.3 linear ft. (14 boxes: 9 document boxes, 3 record cartons 1 half-sized document box 1 small box)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#1478
8494934
The Constance Webb Papers include correspondence, photographs, and drafts of writings by Webb, who was the author of the first biography of Richard Wright and the second wife of C. L. R. James. Webb edited two books of letters by C.L.R. James and materials related to those books can be found here. A few letters written by C.L.R. James and a smattering of material related to his work can also be found in this collection.
History
Writer, actress, and model Constance Webb (1918-2005) was the second wife of C. L. R. James (1901-1989).
Webb, the fifth of six children, was born and raised in Fresno, California. Her parents, Minerva Susan Reynolds Webb, and, George Detwyler Webb, were originally from Atlanta, Georgia. Webb joined the Socialist Party as a teenager; married and divorced two men, Norman Henderson, Jr. and Edward Keller, by the time she was twenty-five; and made her living initially as a model and an actress. She attended Fresno State College briefly, but never graduated from college.
Webb met C. L. R. James in 1939 after he spoke at an event in Los Angeles and shortly thereafter they began corresponding. Webb's side of the correspondence has not survived, but many of James' letters have. The bulk of those surviving letters are at the Schomburg Center in New York.
In the mid-1940s, after her second divorce, Webb left California for New York City. She took a room in the Barbizon Hotel for Women, began modeling for the Harry Conover Agency, continued an affair with Jack Gilford that had begun in California, and contacted James. James introduced Webb to Richard Wright and his wife, Ellen, Chester Himes and Ralph Ellison. Webb accompanied James when he attended the meetings of various Socialist organizations including the Johnson-Forest Tendency or Johnsonites, a small group for which James wrote under the byline "J. R. Johnson" and Raya Dunayevskaya, as "Freddie Forest". Webb began writing, too, a vocation that would outlast her acting and modeling careers. Her article, "What Next for Richard Wright?" was published in Phylon in 1949. In 1946 she printed privately, and distributed, "A hitherto unpublished manuscript by Richard Wright being a continuation of Black Boy." Webb and James married in 1946.
Webb and James' marriage lasted in fits and starts for nearly seven years. In 1949 C. L. R. James, Jr., "Nobbie", their only child was born. They were separated forcibly in 1952, by James' arrest and detention on Ellis Island. In 1953, facing deportation, C. L. R. James left the United States, his home for 15 years, for England; Webb remained in New York with Nobbie. Through their parenting of Nobbie--Robert as an adult--Webb and James renewed their correspondence.
From the early 1950s through the early 1970s, Webb worked as an executive secretary or administrative assistant in a variety of businesses, first in New York and then in Los Angeles where she moved in 1970. During the 1950s Webb wrote for Correspondence, the Johnsonite newspaper, and accepted free lance projects. After a brief sabbatical from secretarial work, Webb's first book, Richard Wright: A Biography, was published in 1968.
By the end of the nineteen-fifties Webb was married to Edward W. Pearlstien (1928-2001), her fourth and last husband. Edward, a writer and a teacher, taught history at the Fieldston School, New York University and Hunter College. They remained married for over thirty years, a union that ended only with his death. Webb and Pearlstien worked together in their later years at Editorial Consultants, Inc., which they had founded along with Annette Welles in 1971. Editorial Consultants produced, primarily, reports, manuals and brochures for professional organizations. From 1973 until her retirement in 1987 Webb also worked as a technical writer for the Bechtel Power Corporation in San Francisco, California.
In 1985 Webb, concerned about James' deteriorating health, wrote to his assistant, Anna Grimshaw, an anthropologist and recent graduate of Cambridge University, with advice on his care. This letter was the beginning of a two-decades-long relationship sustained through correspondence and their collaboration on several C. L. R. James-related projects. Webb also kept in contact with a variety of other C. L. R. James scholars and Richard Wright scholars.
In retirement Webb took on a series of writing projects. She transcribed and edited, with Anna Grimshaw, two collections of C. L. R. James letters: Special Delivery: The Letters of C.L.R. James to Constance Webb, 1939-1948 (1996) and The Nobbie Stories for Children and Adults, which was published posthumously (2006). She published a memoir of the first half of her life, Not Without Love: Memoirs (2003) and wrote several extensive drafts of a novel. The novel was left unfinished when Webb died in 2005.
Scope and Content
The Constance Webb Papers include correspondence, photographs, and drafts of writings by Webb. Webb edited two books of letters by C.L.R. James and materials related to those books can be found here. A few letters written by C.L.R. James and a smattering of material related to his work can also be found in this collection.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in five series:
Series I: C. L. R. James, 1932-1991
Series II: Richard Wright, 1940s-2001
Subseries II.1: Correspondence, 1940s-1994
Subseries II.2: Writings, 1940s-2001
Series III: Correspondence, 1940s-2005
Series IV: Writings, 1940s-2002
Series V: Personal, 1918-2002
Subjects
Grimshaw, Anna.; Himes, Lesley.; James, C. L. R. (Cyril Lionel Robert), 1901-1989.; Pearlstien, Edward W., 1928-; Rowley, Hazel.; Webb, Constance.; Wright, Richard, 1908-1960.; Correspondence
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
Constance Webb Gift 2009
Related Material at Columbia
C.L.R. James Papers Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Anna Grimshaw Papers Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Darcus Howe Papers Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Related Material at Other Repositiories
Martin and Jessie Glaberman Collection, Walter P. Reuther Library, Wayne State University, Detroit, Michigan.
C.L.R. James Letters, Schomburg Center, New York Public Library, New York, New York
Richard Wright Collection, Schomburg Center, New York Public Library, New York, New York
- Series I: C.L.R. James, 1932-1991
  The bulk of this series comprises transcriptions of letters from James to Constance Webb and to their son, C. L. R. James, Jr. and other materials related to Special Delivery: The Letters of C.L. R. James to Constance Webb, 1939-1948 and The Nobbie Stories for Children and Adults, the two books of James' correspondence edited by Webb. Much of the other correspondence found here between Webb and James relates to their son, C. L. R. James, Jr., and many of these letters are transcriptions or photocopies. (Many of the original copies of James' letters to Webb, and to his son, are held at the Schomburg Center.) This series also includes a small amount of correspondence by James to others, a typescript draft of American Civilization along with a few other pieces by James, and writings and materials related to the Johnson-Forest Tendency.
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - General, 1970, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - C. L. R. James to [Daniel] Bell, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - C. L. R. James to Grace [Lee Boggs], 1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - C. L. R. James to Constance Webb and C. L. R. James, Jr., 1941-1986, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Constance Webb to C. L. R. James, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - C. L. R. James and Constance Webb--To and From, 1959-1980s (3 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 7 to 9)
    - Regarding C. L. R. James, Jr.,circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Constance Webb--London Trips, 1982, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Johnson-Forest Tendency
    - General, 1955-1956, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Conference--Transcript, Circa 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Karl Marx, Three Essays by--with Introduction, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - "On W", 1955, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - "REB"
      - General, 1955 January-March (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Circular Letters, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Finance Campaign, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Finance Campaign--Detroit, Circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Finance Campaign--Los Angeles, 1955, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - The Paper, Circa mid-1950s (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Report--Correspondence, Circa mid-1950s (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Seminar on New Human Relations, Circa mid-1950s (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - State Capitalism and World Revolution, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Webb, Constance-- FBI Surveillance, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Webb, Constance-- Letter to Cecelia [Weinstein Lang], 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The Nobbie Stories for Children and Adults
    - C. L. R. James to Choongko (C. L. R. James, Jr.), 1954-1957, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - C. L. R. James to Choongko-- Photocopies, 1953-1957, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Introduction--Drafts--by Constance Webb, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Manuscript, 2004, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Special Delivery: The Letters of C.L.R. James to Constance Webb, 1939-1948
    - C. L. R. James to Constance Webb--Transcriptions, 1939-1945, (4 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 7 to 10)
    - C. L. R. James to Constance Webb--Transcriptions, 1946-1951, Undated, (5 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 1 to 5)
    - C. L. R. James--To and From--Transcriptions and Photocopies, 1959-1980s (3 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 6 to 8)
    - Book Proposals, 1986-1993 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Contracts and Permissions, 1986-1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Editing--General, circa 1980s (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Manuscript--Drafts, circa 1980s, (3 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Writings by James
    - "Abolition Movement--Its Meaning Today", 1963 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - American Civilization--Manuscript, circa 1950s (bound typescript) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Cultural Correspondence--Articles, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "Education, Propaganda, Agitation; Post-War America and Bolshevism", Circa 1945 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Trinidad Speech--Transcription, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Writings About James
    - Anna Grimshaw, 1990, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Constance Webb, 1986, Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Printed Material
    - Clippings, 1984-2001 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Death of C.L.R. James, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Exhibits and Events,1959-1991 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Fourth International--"Marxism and the Negro", 1950 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Marxist Quarterly, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Series II: Richard Wright, Circa 1940s-2001
  Included in this series are correspondence and materials related to Webb's biography of Richard Wright and other writings of hers that concerned Wright.
  - Sub-series II.1: Correspondence Regarding--To and From
    This sub-series contains correspondence to and from Webb and others regarding her research of Richard Wright's life and work, and inquiries to her after the publication of the Wright biography. There are two letters by Wright to Margrit de Sablonier, the Dutch translator of Wright's work.
    - General, Circa 1940s-1970s, (4 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 13 to 16)
    - General, 1980s-2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - General--Agent, 1967-1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Aaron, Abe and Chester, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Bontemps, Arna, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Brown, Joe, 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Conroy, Jack, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Ellison, Ralph, 1967-1967 (Photocopies) (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Fabre, Michel, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Himes, Chester, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - de Sablonier, Margrit, 1966-1968, Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Schapiro, Meyer, 1948, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Wittenber, Jan, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Wright Family, 1961-1970, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Wright, Richard to Margrit de Sablonier, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Wright, Richard to Margrit de Sablonier, 1954, 1960 (Transcriptions and Photocopies) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Sub-series II.2: Writings
    Held here are an unpublished speech by Wright, and drafts of a continuation of Black Boy. Webb's writing in this sub-series includes drafts of her biography of Wright, encyclopedia entries, Webb's proposal for another Wright project and her notes regarding Ellen Wright.
    - By Wright
      - Black Boy, Continuation of--Draft, Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Black Boy, Continuation of--and Notes, Circa 1940s (Privately Printed) (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - "How 'Bigger' Was Born," 1940 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - "The Position of the Negro Artist and Intellectual in American Society," 1960 (unpublished speech) (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Black Boy, Richard Wright: A Biography
      - Drafts, circa 1940s-1960s (2 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Drafts--Introduction, circa 1960s (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Notes--Paris, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Notes--Paris--Wright's Files, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Notes--Preliminary, Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Publishing Materials, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Wright, Ellen, Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Other
      - Clippings, 1960-2001 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Documentary Proposal--by A.J. Jaeger, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Encyclopedia Entries--by Webb, 1968-1969, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Black Boy,Richard Wright and 19th Century Novels of Crime--Book Proposal--by Webb, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Thesis--by Susan Surich, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - "What Next for Richard Wright?"--by Webb, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Series III: Correspondence, 1940s-2005
  Correspondents in this series include scholars of C. L. R. James and those concerned with his care; scholars of Richard Wright; and editors, friends and family. Much of the correspondence from the late 1990s through 2005 consists of printed copies of often quite lengthy emails. Anna Grimshaw, Lesley Himes and Hazel Rowley are among those with whom Webb corresponded most frequently. Copies of Webb's letters to many of her correspondents can also be found here. The bulk of the correspondence dates from the 1980s through the early 2003.
  - "Agents," 1987-2002 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Bates, Daisy--Regarding, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Boggs, Grace Lee and James, 1954, 1959, 1998, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Buhle, Paul, 1983-2000 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Dibb, Mike and Cheli Duran, 1998-2004, Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Dumain, Ralph, 2001-2003 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Feeney, Joan, 1979-1981, Undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Geary, Ida, 1993-2001 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Glaberman, Martin, 1970-2001 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Grimshaw, Anna, 1985-2004, Undated (4 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 10 to 13)
  - Hill, Robert, 1982-1989 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Himes, Chester, 1953-1968 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Himes, Chester--Regarding, 1963-2003, Undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Himes, Lesley, 1993-2004, Undated (2 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 1 to 2)
  - James, C. L. R., Jr., 1950s-1991 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - James-Webb Family, 1940s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Jefferson, Kris--Documentary Proposal, 2002-2003 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Landrigan, John--University Press of New England, 2002-2004 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Margolies, Claire and Edward, 1987, 2001-2005 Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Murray, Jim, 2001-2003 (2 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 8 to 9)
  - Paine, Lyman and Frances, "Freddy", 1978-1986 Undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Pearlstien, Edward, 1970-1986 Undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Pease, Donald, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Phillips, Caryl, 1996-2004 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Ross, Lynn, 1974-1981 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Rowley, Hazel, 1997-2005, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 5 to 6)
  - Sallis, James, 1998-2002 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Schomberg Collection, 1986-1992 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Black Boy, Special Delivery--Regarding, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - University of Nebraska Press--Black Boy, The Nobbie Stories, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Warkentin, Alfred--Writing Proposals, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Chronological, 1940s-1970s (3 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 12 to 14)
  - Chronological, 1980s-2000s, Undated (4 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 1 to 4)
- Series IV: Writings, 1940s-2002, Undated
  The manuscripts and editorial materials for The Nobbie Stories for Children and Adults and Special Delivery: The Letters of C.L.R. James to Constance Webb, 1939-1948, both edited by Webb can be found in the Series I: C. L. R. James, 1932-1991. In this series are poetry, drafts of Webb's memoir, Not Without Love: Memoirs, multiple drafts of an unpublished novel and a few clippings of articles by Webb. A few pieces written by others, including Webb's husband Edward Pearlstien are also included here.
  - By Webb
    - Articles, 1959-2001, Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Black Boy, Not Without Love: Memoirs (2003)
      - Afterword--Donald Pease, Undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Book Cover, Undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Drafts, Undated (9 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 8 to 16)
      - Manuscript, Undated (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 17 to 18)
      - Notes, Undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - Publication Materials, 2002, Undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Poetry--"Miss Mrs Ms", Undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Poetry, 1940s-1970s, (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Notebooks, Undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Notes and Ideas, Undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Unpublished
      - Black Boy, Black Redeemer: The Memoirs of Victoria Wright, Undated (2 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 1 to 2)
      - "Black/White Relations"--Notes and Drafts, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Black Boy, How I Was Tormented by Blacks (Negroes): The Memoirs of Victoria Wright, Undated (5 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 4 to 8)
      - Black Boy, How to Torment Blacks (Negroes): An Exemplary Novel, Undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - "Some Blessed hope", Undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Untitled, Undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Untitled--Pages 1-253, Undated (2 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 12 to 13)
    - Writings by Others
      - Cudjoe, Selwyn R.--Lecture--"The Love Letters of C.L.R. James", 1992 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Duran, Cheli--Black Boy, Special Delivery--Screenplay, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Grimshaw, Anna--"Himalyan Winter", 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - Perlstien, Edward--Archibald Cypres--"Reconstituting the Constitution: An Agenda for Reform", Undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - Perlstien, Edward--Black Boy, Three Intellectual Plays, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - Weinstein, Norman--"On the Inside", Undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - Unidentified--Draft with Edits, circa 1960s (Photocopy) (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Series V: Personal, 1918-2002, Undated
  This series contains an eclectic mix: address books, notebooks, sketches and artwork; employment and personal documents; subject files, materials from two lawsuits; and a Selective Service Appeal regarding C. L. R. James, Jr. Included in the Selective Service Appeal material is correspondence with Conrad Lynn, the New York City civil-rights attorney who represented C.L.R. James, Jr. Also in this series are photographs of Webb, C.L.R. James, and friends and family.
  - Address Books, Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Artwork, Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Artwork--Cats--Computer Generated, Undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Artwork--Sketch Books, Undated (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 4 to 5)
  - Barieau, Bill--Party, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Biographical Blurb, Undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Clippings--General, 1953-2001, Undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Clippings--Constance Webb, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Computer Files--Diskettes, 1992-1996, Undated (14) (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Computer Files--Disks, Undated (8) (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Documents, 1918-1969 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Editorial Consultants, 1971, 2001-2002 (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 11 to 12)
  - Editorial Consultants--Financial Statements, 1984-2001 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Editorial Consultants--Korea Book, 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Employment--Bechtel Power Corporation, 1970-1983 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Employment--Resumes, circa 1970-1980s (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Ephemera, 1950, Undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Europe, Trip to, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Hemstreet, Robert--Unitarian Universalist Church,1977-1984 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Income Taxes, 2000-2002 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - James, C. L. R., Jr.--"Robert"-- Selective Service Appeal, 1967-1974 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Lawsuit--Accident, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Lawsuit--Juror Harassment, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Subject Files
    - General Research, 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Fresno, 1961-1987, Undated (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Puerto Rico, 1961-1968, Undated (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 26 to 27)
  - Will--Constance Webb Pearlstien, 2003-2004 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Photographs--Larger Format
    - Family--Possibly Pearlstien, circa 1920s-1960s (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Family--Unidentified, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - James, C. L. R., Jr.--"Robert", 1950s-1962 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Pearlstien, Edward, circa 1930s-1970s (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Webb, Constance, Circa 1940s-1950s circa 2000s (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Webb-Pearlstien Wedding, circa 1959 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Photographs
    - General, 1960s, Undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - James, C. L. R., circa 1949-1950s (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - James, C. L. R.--Families--Trinidad, circa 1959 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - James, C. L. R., Jr.--"Robert", 1949-1980s (5 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 6 to 10)
    - James, Henno, 1960s (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Pearlstien, Edward, circa 1930s-1990s (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 12 to 13)
    - Pearlstien --Family, circa 1920s-1960s (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Pearlstien, Uncle J., 1963 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Trotsky, Leon, Undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Webb, Constance
      - circa 1920s-1990s (7 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 17 to 24)
      - and Selma James, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 24)
      - Paintings, Undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
      - Queen of Fresno, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 27)
      - Washington, DC--March on, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Webb Family, circa 1950s-1965 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Wright, Ellen, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Wright, Richard--First Wife--Dheema Meidman, Undated (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Unidentified
      - Baby Photos, 1929-1949, Undated (Box 14, Folder 32)
      - Family Photos, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 14, Folder 33)
      - Groups, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 14, Folder 34)
      - Individuals, circa 1960s-1990s (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 35 to 36)
    - Photographs--Other
      - JPEGS on Disk--8, Undated (Box 14, Folder 37)
      - Negatives, Undated (Box 14, Folder 38)
      - Slides, Undated (Box 14, Folder 39)